datastax.com 2019-07-06

# DataStax Website Privacy Policy | DataStax

**Effective: 25 May 2018**

## 1\. Introduction

We know that you care about how the information we receive about you (which may include Personal Data) is used and shared, and we take your privacy seriously.  

This privacy policy is the notice which explains how DataStax, Inc. and its subsidiaries (together “DataStax,” “our,” “us”, or “we“) collect, use, and share the information (which may include Personal Data) that we receive or collect through: 

  * the websites we operate including (without limitation) the websites at [www.datastax.com](http://www.datastax.com/), [www.datastax.fr](https://www.datastax.fr/), [www.datastax.de](https://www.datastax.de/), [www.datastax.jp](https://www.datastax.jp/), [https://academy.datastax.com](https://academy.datastax.com/) and [https://docs.datastax.com](https://docs.datastax.com/) (the “Website“); and 
  * other interactions in the course of our publicity, marketing and related activities. 

Our primary goals in collecting information are: 

  * to understand you and to enable us to best respond to your requests for information; 
  * to improve the Website, its features and other other documentation and content; and 
  * to promote our business interests, products and services (both through the Website and through other activities such as events, marketing, conferences, community meet-ups and so on).  

This policy also sets out the rights you have to control the use of your information.  You can request a copy of this policy by contacting us at [privacy@datastax.com](mailto:privacy@datastax.com).

This policy does not apply to information that we receive or handle on behalf of our customers in our role as a software or services provider, and any such information is governed by the terms of the applicable agreement. 

In this policy, “Personal Data” is information that directly or indirectly identifies you or another individual, and may include name, title, company name, job function, expertise, postal address, telephone number, email address, browser and device information (including IP Address), and information collected through cookies and other similar technologies. 

## 2\. Information we collect

We may collect information from you through your use of the Website (for example, if you register for a webinar, contact us, download content, or register to use the Website) and offline (for example, when you attend one of our events, during phone calls with sales representatives, or when you contact a DataStax representative).  

It is your choice whether or not to provide information, however if you choose not to provide requested information you may not be able to use certain features of the Website or be provided with certain products or services.

Information may also be gathered from our affiliates and third-party sources including, without limitation, third-party service providers (for example, event organisers and marketing data and fulfilment companies), opt-in lists, publicly available data, and other companies and referrals.  

Like most websites, the Website uses cookies and other automated information collection means: our servers may automatically collect usage information that could include your IP address, cookie information, browser information, the page you request and other website usage patterns.  For more information about the cookies and similar technologies we use, and how you can control them, please refer to the section entitled “Additional information about cookies, tracking pixels and related technologies”. 

## 3\. How your information may be used

We may use your information (including, where applicable, Personal Data) to support and develop your relationship with DataStax and your use and understanding of our products and services, and to promote our business, products and services.  

The ways and contexts in which we use information about you include:

  * **To provide materials you request.  **We provide a number of ways for you to request materials from us, such as newsletters, brochures, product literature and the like.  We may collect and use contact name, title, contact information, preferences, and other information relevant to responding to your request.
  * **To process registrations.  **You may be given an opportunity to register for a variety of reasons (for example, to create an account, to receive communications, to attend an event, to join/participate in an online community or other interactive areas, to receive training or to take an exam for a DataStax certification, and so on).  Such activities may entail collection of your name, title, contact information, your username and password, experiences with our products and information/preferences related to the subject matter of the particular activity. 
  * **To follow up with you.  **When you attend an event where DataStax is present, you might fill in an optional form, telling us your name, title, email address, whether you attended past events, your postal code, comments, whether you would like us to contact you in the future and/or other information.  Likewise, you might choose to participate in an online or offline survey where you provide information and survey-specific preference data. 
  * **To operate the Website.  **We use information to maintain, secure and improve the Website, to help you quickly find information on the Website, and to understand your interests when visiting the Website.  We do analytics to understand your behaviors and to improve the Website for all of our users.
  * **To tell you about our business.  **We may use information to contact you to tell you about about our business, products and services.  We do this in our legitimate interests in promoting and selling our products and services. 
  * **For other marketing purposes.**  DataStax may use your contact information to tell you about other products and services that we believe might be of interest provided you have indicated that you are happy to be contacted for these purposes.  If at any time you do not want communications from DataStax for promotional purposes or do not want us to share your information with our third party partners for promotional purposes, please let us know (see the section entitled “Opting Out”).

## 4\. How we may share your information

We may disclose the information you provide (including, where applicable, Personal Data) to third–parties including our affiliates, consultants and the contractors that we use to support our business and operations (for example, advertising and PR service providers, event-related services, delivery and fulfilment services, and other web-related services such as web-hosting and web-monitoring services) who have agreed to keep the information confidential and use it only to provide the applicable service(s). In some cases, we work with companies that help us to communicate with you.  

DataStax may also disclose information if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with applicable laws or legal processes, or to protect and defend the rights or property of DataStax or its customers, agents or contractors.  This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection, credit risk reduction and law enforcement purposes. 

If we should ever merge with another organisation, file for bankruptcy, or sell our assets, we may transfer the information you provide to us to a third party or share your information with the company with which we enter into such transaction or process as a part of such transaction or process.

## 5\. Security of your information

We maintain physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards designed to protect your information.  We use secure server software (SSL) and firewalls, designed to protect your information from unauthorised access, disclosure, loss, misuse, alteration, or destruction.  Only authorised personnel amongst our employees and third party service providers have access to your information and only on a ‘need to know’ basis. We internally audit our security and privacy practices and procedures examining confidentiality standards and information access in order to protect your information.  Despite the actions and precautions we take, no data transmissions over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. Consequently, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of your information and you transmit it to us at your own risk.

We may send an email to you at the email address you have provided to us in the event of a security breach.  Depending on where you live and the circumstances of the breach, you may have a legal right to receive notice of a security breach in writing.  To receive free written notice of a security breach (or to withdraw your consent from receiving electronic notice) you should notify us at [privacy@datastax.com](mailto:privacy@datastax.com).

## 6\. Opting out

If at any point you no longer wish to receive marketing communications (which includes information about new product/service notices, email newsletters or other future communications from us) please follow the opt-out instructions included in our confirmation email and in each communication.  

If you have registered an account on the Website, opting out of receiving marketing messages will not apply to information provided to us as a result of signing up to use the Website and we reserve the right to send you necessary account notices or other administrative and transactional notices.

## 7\. How long we keep your information

We retain your information (including Personal Data, where applicable) for as long as you remain an active user of the Website, in order for us to meet our contractual obligations to you, and for such longer period(s) as are legally permitted.  We may also retain aggregated information beyond this time for research purposes and to help us develop and improve our services (you cannot be identified from aggregate information retained or used for these purposes). 

We may need to retain certain information even once an account has been closed or deleted for differing periods, depending on the category of information concerned (for example, to enforce our terms, for fraud prevention, to identify, issue or resolve any legal claims, for proper record keeping purposes and/or as required for our business operations or by applicable laws).  

We may also retain a record of any stated objection by you to receiving DataStax updates for the purpose of ensuring we can continue to respect your wishes and not contact you further.  

## 8\. Third-party websites and technologies

Please be aware that other websites, including the websites of third parties that you connect with through the Website, may collect your information (including Personal Data).  This policy does not cover the information practices of those third-party websites. Further, the Website may employ third party technologies that require you to accept such third party’s terms.  This policy does not cover the information practices of those third-party technologies.

## 9\. Website privacy policy changes

We may change this policy by posting a new version of this privacy policy on this Website.  When we do change the policy, we will also revise the “effective” date at the top of this page and will notify you of any material changes before they take effect either through the Website or by sending you a notification.  Any such material changes will only apply to Personal Data collected after the revised privacy policy took effect.  Your continued use of this Website following such changes constitutes your acceptance of the revised policy.

## 10\. Contacting us

If you have any questions, comments or concerns regarding this privacy policy or any questions about the security of the Website, please contact us by email at [privacy@datastax.com](mailto:privacy@DataStax.com).  

## 11\. Additional notices

**Notices for California users**

At this time, we do not respond to ‘Do Not Track’ browser settings or signals. In addition, we may use other technology that is standard to the internet, such as pixel tags, web beacons, and other similar technologies, to track visitors to our site. Those tools may be used by us and by third parties to collect information about you and your internet activity, even if you have turned on the Do Not Track signal. 

Under California Civil Code Section 1789.3, California website users are entitled to the following specific consumer rights notice: The Complaint Assistance Unit of the Division of Consumer Services of the California Department of Consumer Affairs may be contacted in writing at 400 R Street, Suite 1080, Sacramento, California 95814, or by telephone at (916) 445-1254 or (800) 952-5210.

**Notices for European Economic Area (EEA) users**

Under EU data protection laws (including General Data Protection Regulation 2016/679 (“GDPR”)) you have the right under certain circumstances to receive a copy of your Personal Data held by us, request the correction, rectification or erasure of your Personal Data, and request that we cease processing of your Personal Data.  You can exercise these rights by contacting us at [privacy@datastax.com](mailto:privacy@datastax.com).  We may need to request specific information from you to confirm your identity and ensure you have the right to access this information, to ensure that your Personal Data is not disclosed to any individual who does not have the right to receive it.  We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request in order to speed up our response time. We will respond to your request within 30 days. When we delete information it will be deleted from the active database but may remain in our archives.  

If a request or concern is not satisfactorily resolved by us, you may approach your local data protection supervisory authority.  The Information Commissioner (ICO) is the supervisory authority in the UK and can provide further information about your rights and our obligations in relation to your Personal Data, as well as deal with any complaints that you may have about our processing of your information.  See [here](https://ico.org.uk/) for more information.

**Lawful basis for processing Personal Data that we collect about you**

EU data protection laws contain a number of lawful bases under which processing of Personal Data is permitted.  For our EEA users we have been careful to ensure we have a lawful basis for processing all Personal Data that we have.  

Our lawful bases include:

  * **Performing a contract we have with you** – in certain circumstances we need your Personal Data to comply with an obligation to deliver products and services.  For example, if you want to use our software products and download them through the Website, we need your name and contact details so we can communicate with you and provide the software.
  * **Legal compliance** – sometimes the law says we can or need to collect and use your information.  For example, we can pass on details of people involved in fraud or other criminal activity to law enforcement.
  * **Legitimate interests** – this is a basis for processing found in EU data protection laws which permits processing where we have a good and fair reason to use your information, and do so in ways which do not hurt your rights, freedom and/or interests.  We sometimes need your information to pursue our legitimate interests in ways which might reasonably be expected as part of running our business and which do not materially impact your rights, freedom and/or interests. For example, we will send you promotional communications about our products and services, subject to your legal rights to control whether we do so.  

**Transfers of Personal Data**

If you are located in the EEA for the purposes of GDPR and any corresponding or equivalent national implementing law or regulations, DataStax, Inc. is the data controller with respect to any Personal Data collected by it, and that information may then be transferred to DataStax, Inc’s subsidiaries in the EEA (including DataStax UK Limited) which may also act as a data controller in relation to that information in order to perform the activities described in this policy.  The address of and contact details for these entities is available on the Website [here](https://www.datastax.com/company#offices). 

Any information (including Personal Data) which we collect is stored on secure servers in the US operated by DataStax or its service providers.  Personal Data may be transferred by us to our other offices and/or to third parties mentioned in the circumstances described above (see the section entitled “How we may share your information”), which may be situated outside the EEA and may be processed by staff operating outside the EEA.  

Where we transfer your Personal Data we will take all reasonable steps to ensure that your privacy rights are protected which may include entering into European Commission-approved standard contractual clauses relevant to transfers of Personal Data outside the EEA.

## 12\. Additional information about cookies, tracking pixels and related technologies

When you visit the Website, we and our third-party service providers (which may include third-party analytics service providers and third-party advertisers) use technologies such as cookies, tracking pixels, server logs and other similar technologies to collect and store your information and preferences, to track your activity on the Website, and to enhance the functionality of the Website.  

The data collected may include usage statistics, Website traffic and performance data, and other information such as your IP address, the type of internet browser or device you use, any website you have come to the Website from and your operating system.  The information collected may include your Personal Data.

We use the following technologies on the Website: 

  * **Cookies.  **Cookies are information about you that is stored on your browser or hard drive and may be set by us or by third parties who are delivering services on our behalf.  Certain cookies on the Website last only for the duration of your session and expire when you close the browser. Other cookies are used to remember you when you return to the Website and so last for longer.  Many cookies are are necessary for Website operational purposes or used to save you time (for example, so that you do not need to manually re-enter your information when you log back in).  
  
**‘Targeting’, ‘advertising’ and ‘re-targeting’ cookies.**  These cookies record your visit to the Website, the pages you have visited and the links you have followed.  These help us improve the Website by showing when and how users use the Website. We use this information, subject to your choices, to make the Website and the advertising displayed on it more relevant to your interests, and may also share this information with applicable third parties for this purpose.  We sometimes work with partners to manage our advertising on other websites.  This may involve gathering information through our advertising partners about websites that you visit, so as to place you in a “market segment”. This information is used to place our advertisements based on your browsing activities and interests. Without these cookies, advertisements you encounter will be less relevant to you and to your interests.

If you choose to accept cookies from us and our service providers, you are agreeing to let us and our service providers install cookies on your computer. For more help with cookies see the section entitled “Disabling cookies”.

  * **Web beacons.  **We use web beacons (also known as internet tags or clear GIFs) on the Website to access and set cookies and otherwise help us to better understand how users are moving through the Website.  Information provided by the web beacons include the computer’s IP address, the type of browser being used and the time that the web beacon was viewed.  We also use web beacons in emails and newsletters so that we know when such communications have been opened and to otherwise help us tailor our communications to individual users.  
  * **Pixel tags.  **We also engage third party service providers to serve online advertisements on our behalf.  They may use a “pixel tag” which triggers a cookie to collect information about your visits to the Website and to other websites, and they may use that information and share and combine it with other information with their partners to show you advertisements for goods and services you might be interested in on the Website and on other websites, apps and social media platforms (such as LinkedIn and Facebook) including by observing the kinds of products and subject-matter you are interested in and certain other information. 
  * **Google Tag Manager.  **This service allows website tags to be managed via an interface (tags are small elements of code that are used, for example, to measure traffic and visitor behavior, to understand the effect of online advertising and social channels, to set up re-marketing and orientation towards target groups, and to test and optimise websites).  Google Tag Manager only implements tags. No cookies are used and consequently no Personal Data is recorded. 
  * **Google Analytics.  **To help us improve the Website, we use Google Analytics, a web analytics service.  Google Analytics uses cookies to help us analyse how visitors use the site. The information generated by cookies about your use of the Website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by a Google server in the United States.  Google uses this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on Website activity for our Website operators and providing them with other services relating to Website activity and internet usage. 

**Disabling cookies**

Most web browsers automatically accept cookies but if you do not want to allow cookies on your computer, most browsers have a feature that allows you either to automatically decline cookies, or to decline or accept particular cookies from a particular web site.  

You can learn more about cookies [here](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) (which includes additional useful information on cookies and how to block cookies using different types of browsers). 

You can prevent the storage of data relating to your use of the Website and created via the cookie (including your IP address) by Google Analytics by downloading and installing the browser plug-in available [here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en).  

For more information about behavioral advertising cookies and about how to turn these features off please refer to the information available [here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/) or [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/). 

If you choose to reject cookies from the Website, the content we provide may be of less relevance to you, and you may be unable to use certain Website services, features, and functionality that require registration, customisation, or data tracking. 

## 13\. Additional information about advertising partners and social media platforms

**Our use of advertising partners  **

We sometimes work with advertising networks that gather information about the content on the Website that you visit, and on information on other websites and services that you may visit.  

This may result in you seeing advertisements on the Website or our advertisements when you visit other websites and services of third parties.  

For information about how to turn these features off see [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/).

**Our use of social media platforms  **

We use social media platforms to advertise to you online and to monitor the success of our advertising (for example, by receiving information when you click on our ads on Facebook, LinkedIn and others):

  * **LinkedIn Ads.**  The analysis and conversion tracking technology provided by the social network LinkedIn is integrated into the Website.  When you visit the Website, a connection is established between your browser and the LinkedIn server via the re-marketing tags.  This informs LinkedIn that you visited the Website with your IP address, meaning that LinkedIn can connect your visit to the Website with your your account.  We can use this information to display LinkedIn ads. Please be aware that we as the Website provider do not receive any information about the content of the transferred data or how it is used by LinkedIn.  Further information can be found in LinkedIn’s privacy policy [here](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy).
  * **Marketo.  **We use third party marketing software from a company called Marketo to send our emails.  As mentioned above, we use cookies as part of tracking so we have information on email open rates and click through rates.  We also track activity on the Website. For example, visitors can download marketing white papers from the site and we use Marketo cookies to see who does this and if they then visit other parts of the Website.  For more information on Marketo’s privacy and cookie policy, please see Marketo’s privacy policy [here](http://www.marketo.com/trust/legal/privacy).  
  * **Twitter Advertising.  **We advertise on Twitter and our advertising content will be tailored to your interests on the basis of your browsing behavior and the pages you have consulted on this and other websites.  In order to improve the relevance of our marketing content, the cookie may therefore transmit such data to Twitter, which will use it to better understand your interests. If you decide that you do not wish your browsing data to be collected, you can find comprehensive information on Twitter’s advertising policy and the steps you can take to protect your privacy [here](https://support.twitter.com/articles/20170514).  
  * **Facebook Custom Audience.  **This service from Facebook enables us to display personalised ads to people on our email lists when they visit Facebook.  We provide information such as your email address and phone number in encrypted form to Facebook (so they cannot be seen by anyone at Facebook) to enable Facebook to determine if you are a registered Facebook account holder.  
  * **Facebook Connect.  **We use Facebook Connect to allow you to sign up and log in using your Facebook account.  If you sign up using Facebook Connect, Facebook will ask your permission to share certain information from your Facebook account with us.  This may include your first name, last name, email address in order for us to verify your identity and gender, general location, a link to your Facebook profile, your timezone, birthday, profile picture, your “likes” and your list of friends.  This information is collected by Facebook and is provided to us under the terms of Facebook’s privacy policy [here](https://www.facebook.com/policy.php).  You can control the information that we receive from Facebook using the privacy settings in your Facebook account.
